<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on Bioinformatics</title>
    <link>/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on Bioinformatics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory data analysis of breast cancer transcriptomes</title>
      <link>/reading/06-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/06-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Chapter 7 for Data Science: Basics  Recommended Reading  magrittr package in R for pipes.
 Chapter 8 for Data Science: Projects is very short and we have covered most of this material throughout the lecture. It might be of interest to you.
  Deeper insight  DataCamp tutorial on pipes  Action items  You might investigate the code in Project L06 at RStudio Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction and orientation</title>
      <link>/reading/00-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/00-reading/</guid>
      <description>This is the first class, so allow me to run through how the Readings pages work.
Both Readings and Video should be completed before the actual lecture. The lecture itself is intended for you to ask questions, for me to give out small quizzes/puzzles/questions (for grades), and for me to provide deeper insight into the material.
Required  Please read the Overview for the course.Required reading represents fundamental material that you are expected to master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction and orientation</title>
      <link>/reading/01-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/01-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Please read the Resources for the course.
 These are interesting short articles on different approaches towards keeping lab notebooks, and the pros and cons of electronic laboratory notebooks (ELNs) versus traditional paper notebooks. E Pain (2019) Science and R Kwok (2018) Nature.
  Recommended  Read a little bit about RStudio here and specifically RStudio Cloud
 If you have difficulties with Google Drive, this seems like a reasonable tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT for the Life Sciences</title>
      <link>/reading/02-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/02-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Chapter 2 R for Data Science: Introduction (1 page long)  Recommended  Try to understand  Antikythera Mechanism Napier’s Bones and Jacquard Loom The Sun Shadow Board   Fun Reading  Computers over Time Computer Science: some of its flavours:  Algorithms Cryptography Computational Complexity Databases Compilers  Read on-line resources with some passing familarity with computer developments in the 20th century. The Turing Award Suggested readings: The Enigma, or at least the movie The Imitation Game War Games, the best movie ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Representing and Manipulating Data in R</title>
      <link>/reading/04-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/04-reading/</guid>
      <description>  Required  Chapter 4 for Data Science: Basics  Deeper insight  Introduction to R (DataCamp) Datacamp has some excellent short courses in R.  Action items  You might investigate the code in Project L04 at RStudio Cloud.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformations of breast cancer transcriptional cohorts</title>
      <link>/reading/05-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/05-reading/</guid>
      <description>  Required  Chapter 5 for Data Science: Basics
 Simpson’s Paradox
  Recommended Reading  If you didn’t have time previously to explore TCGA, perhaps take a look at the project now.  Deeper insight  dplyr tutorial Datacamp’s dpylyr tutorial  Action items  You might investigate the code in Project L05 at RStudio Cloud.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing breast cancer transcriptomes</title>
      <link>/reading/03-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/03-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required  Chapter 3 R for Data Science: Introduction
 Sequencing by Synthesis
 Sequencing by Synthesis (more background including DNA chemistry)
  Recommended  Transcriptomics Excellent set of slides describing sequencing technologies and trends. Includes nice grpahics about Illumina technology. [From D Beiting, UPenn]
 History of Sequencing and Illumina’s Sequencing by Synthesis[From D Beiting, UPenn]
  Deeper insight  DIY Transcriptomics A nice course covering the central topics of transcriptomic bioinformatic analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>